<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DogPedia</string>
    <string name="dogs_name">Nama Jenis Anjing</string>
    <string name="description">Deskripsi</string>
    <string name="aboutTitle">About</string>
    <string name="aboutName">Christian Michael Mozart Sibatuara</string>
    <string name="aboutEmail">18220068@std.stei.itb.ac.id</string>
    <string name="details_title">Description</string>
    <string name="origin">Origin</string>
    <string name="nickname">Nickname</string>
    <string-array name="data_name">
        <item>Labrador Retriever</item>
        <item>French Bulldog</item>
        <item>German Shepherd</item>
        <item>Golden Retriever</item>
        <item>Bulldog</item>
        <item>Beagle</item>
        <item>Poodle</item>
        <item>Rottweiler</item>
        <item>Yorkshire Terrier</item>
        <item>Dachsund</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_description">
        <item>The Labrador Retriever or simply Labrador is a British breed of retriever gun dog. It was developed in the United Kingdom from fishing dogs imported from the colony of Newfoundland (now a province of Canada), and was named after the Labrador region of that colony. It is among the most commonly kept dogs in several countries, particularly in the Western world.\n\nThe Labrador is friendly, energetic, and playful. It was bred as a sporting and hunting dog but is widely kept as a companion dog. It may also be trained as a guide or assistance dog, or for rescue or therapy work.\n\nIn the 1830s, the 10th Earl of Home and his nephews, the 5th Duke of Buccleuch and Lord John Scott, imported progenitors of the breed from Newfoundland to Europe for use as gun dogs. Another early advocate of these Newfoundland fishing dogs was the 2nd Earl of Malmesbury, who bred them for their expertise in waterfowling.\n\nDuring the 1880s, the 3rd Earl of Malmesbury, the 6th Duke of Buccleuch, and the 12th Earl of Home collaborated to develop and establish the Labrador Retriever breed. The dogs Buccleuch Avon and Buccleuch Ned, given by Malmesbury to Buccleuch, were mated with bitches carrying blood from those originally imported by the 5th Duke and the 10th Earl of Home. The offspring are the ancestors of all modern Labradors.</item>
        <item>"The French Bulldog is a French breed of companion dog or toy dog. It appeared in Paris in the mid-nineteenth century, apparently the result of cross-breeding of Toy Bulldogs imported from England and local Parisian ratters.\n\nIt is commonly kept as a pet, and is among the most frequently registered dogs in a number of countries including Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States.\n\nFrom the beginning of the nineteenth century bulldogs were bred in the United Kingdom for purposes other than traditional blood sports such as bull-baiting, which were banned in 1835. By the middle of the century there were miniature bulldogs, often weighing some 7–11 kg (15–24 lb), though some weighed considerably less.\n\nAt the same time, lace workers from Nottingham who were displaced by the Industrial Revolution began to settle in Normandy, France. They brought a variety of dogs with them, including Toy Bulldogs. The dogs became popular in France and a trade in imported small Bulldogs was created, with breeders in England sending over Bulldogs that they considered to be too small, or with faults such as ears that stood up. By 1860, there were few Toy Bulldogs left in England, such was their popularity in France, and due to the exploits of specialist dog exporters.\n\nThe small Bulldog type gradually became thought of as a breed, and received a name, the Bouledogue Francais. This Francization of the English name is also a contraction of the words boule (ball) and dogue (mastiff). The dogs were highly fashionable and were sought after by society ladies and Parisian prostitutes alike, as well as creatives such as artists, writers, and fashion designers. The artists Edgar Degas and Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec are thought to have French Bulldogs in their paintings. However, records were not kept of the breed's development as it diverged further away from its original Bulldog roots. As it changed, terrier stock had been brought in to develop traits such as the breed's long straight ears."</item>
        <item>"The German Shepherd or Alsatian is a German breed of working dog of medium to large size. The breed was developed by Max von Stephanitz using various traditional German herding dogs from 1899.\n\nIt was originally bred as a herding dog, for herding sheep. It has since been used in many other types of work, including disability assistance, search-and-rescue, police work, and warfare. It is commonly kept as a companion dog, and according to the Fédération Cynologique Internationale had the second-highest number of annual registrations in 2013.\n\nGerman Shepherds are medium to large-sized dogs. The breed standard height at the withers is 60–65 cm (24–26 in) for males, and 55–60 cm (22–24 in) for females. German Shepherds are longer than they are tall, with an ideal proportion of 10 to 8+1⁄2. The AKC official breed standard does not set a standard weight range. They have a domed forehead, a long square-cut muzzle with strong jaws and a black nose. The eyes are medium-sized and brown. The ears are large and stand erect, open at the front and parallel, but they often are pulled back during movement. A German Shepherd has a long neck, which is raised when excited and lowered when moving at a fast pace as well as stalking. The tail is bushy and reaches to the hock.\n\nGerman Shepherds have a double coat which is close and dense with a thick undercoat. The coat is accepted in two variants: medium and long. The gene for long hair is recessive, and therefore the long-haired variety is rarer. Treatment of the long-haired variation differs across standards; it is accepted but does not compete against standard-coated dogs under the German and UK Kennel Clubs while it can compete with standard-coated dogs, but is considered a fault, in the American Kennel Club. The FCI accepted the long-haired type in 2010, listing it as the variety b, while the short-haired type is listed as the variety a.\n\nMost commonly, German Shepherds are either tan/black or red/black. Most colour varieties have black masks and black body markings which can range from a classic "saddle" to an overall "blanket". Rarer colour variations include sable, pure-black, pure-white, liver, silver, blue, and panda varieties. The all-black and sable varieties are acceptable according to most standards; however, the blue and liver are considered to be serious faults and the all-white is grounds for instant disqualification from showing in conformation at All Breed and Specialty Shows."</item>
        <item>"The Golden Retriever is a breed of dog that is renowned for its friendly nature, intelligence, and loyalty. They are classified as a medium to large–sized breed and are a popular choice for families due to their loving and gentle disposition. The breed was originally developed in Scotland in the 19th century, where they were used for hunting and retrieving game birds.\n\nGolden Retrievers are known for their beautiful golden coat that can range from pale cream to deep golden. Their coat is thick and water–resistant, which made them perfect for retrieving game from the water. They have a muscular build and stand at around 23–24 inches tall for males and 21–22 inches tall for females. Their weight ranges from 55–75 pounds for males and 55–65 pounds for females.\n\nOne of the standout traits of Golden Retrievers is their friendly nature. They are affectionate and loyal dogs that love nothing more than spending time with their owners. They are great with children and make fantastic family pets. Their friendly nature also makes them well–suited to therapy work, as they can provide comfort and support to those in need.\n\nGolden Retrievers are also intelligent dogs that are easy to train. They are eager to please their owners and are quick learners. This makes them a popular choice for obedience and agility training. They also excel at retrieving, as this is what they were originally bred for.\n\nDue to their friendly nature, Golden Retrievers are not great watchdogs. They are more likely to greet strangers with a wagging tail than to bark or growl. However, they will bark if they sense a threat to their family or home.\n\nGolden Retrievers are generally healthy dogs, although they can be prone to certain health issues such as hip dysplasia, elbow dysplasia, and cataracts. It is important to ensure that they receive regular veterinary checkups to maintain their health."</item>
        <item>"The English Bulldog, or simply Bulldog, is a small to medium-sized breed of dog that is instantly recognizable for its iconic wrinkled face, stocky build, and powerful jaw. Bulldogs are known for their friendly and docile personalities, which makes them a popular choice for families and individuals alike.\n\nThe Bulldog originated in England and was initially bred for bull-baiting, a cruel sport in which a dog would attack and immobilize a bull. When bull-baiting was banned in England in 1835, the Bulldog's aggressive traits were selectively bred out, and the breed evolved into the friendly and gentle companion we know today.\n\nBulldogs have a distinctive appearance that sets them apart from other breeds. They have a short, smooth coat that can be found in various colors such as brindle, white, fawn, and red. Bulldogs have a compact, muscular build and are typically around 12-16 inches tall and weigh between 40-50 pounds.\n\nOne of the most recognizable features of the Bulldog is its wrinkled face, which can require some extra care to keep clean and healthy. Their faces are prone to skin infections, so regular cleaning and wiping of their wrinkles is essential to keep them healthy and comfortable.\n\nDespite their tough appearance, Bulldogs are known for their friendly and gentle nature. They are great with children and make loyal and devoted companions. Bulldogs can be stubborn at times, but they are also intelligent and eager to please their owners, making them trainable with patience and positive reinforcement.\n\nDue to their laid-back personalities, Bulldogs are not particularly active dogs and do not require a lot of exercise. They are content to lounge around the house and are well-suited to apartment living. However, regular short walks and playtime are still important to keep them healthy and prevent obesity.\n\nBulldogs are generally healthy dogs, but like all breeds, they can be prone to certain health issues such as hip dysplasia, skin infections, and respiratory problems due to their flat faces. It's important to ensure they receive regular veterinary checkups and maintain a healthy diet and exercise regimen to keep them healthy."</item>
        <item>"The Beagle is a popular breed of dog that is known for its friendly personality, curious nature, and distinctive appearance. This medium-sized breed is a favorite among families and hunters alike due to their loyal and playful disposition.\n\nThe Beagle is a sturdy and muscular dog that stands at around 13-15 inches tall at the shoulder and weighs between 18-30 pounds. They have a short, dense coat that comes in a variety of colors, including tricolor, red and white, and lemon and white. Their long ears, droopy eyes, and wagging tail make them easily recognizable.\n\nBeagles are energetic dogs that love to play and explore. They have a high level of curiosity and a strong sense of smell, which can sometimes lead them into trouble. As a result, it is important to keep them on a leash when outside and provide them with plenty of exercise and mental stimulation.\n\nOne of the most endearing qualities of the Beagle is their friendly and outgoing nature. They are known for being social dogs that enjoy the company of people and other dogs. They are great with children and make excellent family pets.\n\nBeagles are also intelligent dogs that are quick learners. They respond well to positive reinforcement training techniques and excel in obedience and agility competitions. However, they can be stubborn at times, so it is important to be patient and consistent when training them.\n\nDue to their strong sense of smell, Beagles have been used for hunting for centuries. They were originally bred to track and hunt small game, such as rabbits and hares. However, today most Beagles are kept as companion animals and are not used for hunting.\n\nBeagles are generally healthy dogs, but like all breeds, they can be prone to certain health issues. Some of the most common health problems in Beagles include hip dysplasia, epilepsy, and eye disorders. It is important to ensure that they receive regular veterinary checkups and are fed a healthy diet to maintain their health."</item>
        <item>"The Poodle is a breed of dog that is known for its distinctive curly coat and its elegant, regal appearance. Poodles are a highly intelligent breed and are widely considered to be one of the most trainable breeds of dog.\n\nPoodles come in three different sizes - Standard, Miniature, and Toy. The Standard Poodle is the largest of the three, standing at around 15 inches tall at the shoulder and weighing between 45 and 70 pounds. The Miniature Poodle stands between 10 and 15 inches tall at the shoulder and weighs between 10 and 15 pounds, while the Toy Poodle is the smallest, standing at around 10 inches tall at the shoulder and weighing between 5 and 10 pounds.\n\nOne of the most distinctive features of the Poodle is its coat, which is curly and thick. Poodles have hair instead of fur, which means that they are a hypoallergenic breed and are a good choice for people who suffer from allergies. Poodles come in a wide variety of colors, including white, black, brown, and apricot.\n\nPoodles are highly intelligent dogs that are known for their trainability. They are quick learners and respond well to positive reinforcement training methods. Poodles excel in obedience and agility competitions and are often used as assistance dogs for people with disabilities.\n\nPoodles are also highly social dogs that thrive on human companionship. They are affectionate and loyal to their owners and are good with children. Poodles are highly adaptable and can live in a variety of environments, from apartments to large homes with yards.\n\nPoodles are generally healthy dogs, although they can be prone to certain health issues such as hip dysplasia, epilepsy, and eye problems. It is important to ensure that they receive regular veterinary checkups to maintain their health."</item>
        <item>"The Rottweiler is a large and muscular breed of dog that originated in Germany. They were originally bred for herding and protecting livestock, as well as for pulling carts and carrying supplies for butchers. Today, they are used as working dogs, as well as family pets.\n\nRottweilers have a distinctive appearance, with a short, glossy black coat and tan markings on their face, chest, and legs. They are a powerful breed, with males standing at around 24-27 inches tall and weighing between 95-135 pounds, while females are slightly smaller, standing at around 22-25 inches tall and weighing between 80-100 pounds.\n\nDespite their imposing appearance, Rottweilers are known for their loyalty and affection towards their family. They are intelligent dogs that can be trained to excel in obedience, agility, and protection work. They are also protective of their family and can be wary of strangers, which makes them effective watchdogs. However, it is important to socialize them properly from a young age to ensure that they do not become overly aggressive.\n\nRottweilers are generally healthy dogs, although they can be prone to certain health issues such as hip dysplasia, elbow dysplasia, and bloat. It is important to ensure that they receive regular veterinary checkups and maintain a healthy diet and exercise routine.\n\nWhen it comes to their temperament, Rottweilers can be affectionate and loving towards their family, but they also require a strong and confident owner who can establish themselves as the alpha in the relationship. They are not recommended for inexperienced dog owners or those who are unable to provide them with the exercise and training that they require.\n\nDespite their protective nature, Rottweilers can get along well with children and other pets if they are socialized properly from a young age. However, they should always be supervised around children, as their size and strength can be overwhelming for younger kids."</item>
        <item>"The Yorkshire Terrier, also known as the "Yorkie," is a small breed of dog that originated in England in the 19th century. They were originally bred to catch rats in the textile mills of Yorkshire, England. Today, they are a popular breed of companion dog due to their small size, loyalty, and affectionate nature.\n\nYorkshire Terriers are a toy breed and are one of the smallest breeds of dog. They typically stand at around 8-9 inches tall and weigh between 4-7 pounds. They have a long, silky coat that comes in various shades of blue and tan. Their coat is hypoallergenic, which makes them a good choice for people with allergies.\n\nOne of the standout traits of the Yorkshire Terrier is their loyalty and affectionate nature. They are known for being devoted to their owners and are often referred to as "velcro dogs" because they like to be close to their owners at all times. They are also known for being energetic and playful, despite their small size.\n\nYorkshire Terriers are intelligent dogs that are easy to train. They are eager to please their owners and respond well to positive reinforcement training methods. They are also a relatively low-maintenance breed when it comes to exercise, as they can get enough exercise simply by playing indoors or going for short walks.\n\nDespite their small size, Yorkshire Terriers can be quite vocal and may bark excessively if not trained properly. They can also be prone to separation anxiety if left alone for long periods of time.\n\nYorkshire Terriers are generally a healthy breed, although they can be prone to certain health issues such as dental problems, eye problems, and joint issues. It is important to ensure that they receive regular veterinary checkups to maintain their health."</item>
        <item>"The Dachshund, also known as the "wiener dog," is a small breed of dog that was originally developed in Germany. The breed was created to hunt badgers, rabbits, and other small game. Today, they are popular family pets due to their friendly and playful nature.\n\nDachshunds come in three different coat types: smooth, wirehaired, and longhaired. The smooth coat is the most common and is short and shiny. The wirehaired coat is rough and thick, while the longhaired coat is soft and silky. They are small dogs, weighing between 16 and 32 pounds and standing between 8 and 9 inches tall at the shoulder.\n\nOne of the most distinctive features of Dachshunds is their long, low body. This unique body shape is a result of selective breeding for their hunting abilities. Their short legs and long body allow them to dig into tunnels and burrows to track their prey.\n\nDachshunds are known for their friendly and playful personalities. They are loyal to their families and enjoy spending time with them. They are also social dogs that get along well with other dogs and children. However, they can be stubborn and independent at times, which can make training a challenge.\n\nAs hunting dogs, Dachshunds have a strong prey drive and love to chase small animals. This can be a problem if they are not trained properly or if they are left unsupervised in a yard with small pets. They are also prone to barking, which can make them unsuitable for apartment living or for families with close neighbors.\n\nDachshunds are generally healthy dogs, but they are prone to certain health issues such as intervertebral disc disease (IVDD), which is a condition that affects their spine. This can cause back pain, paralysis, and even death in severe cases. Other health issues that Dachshunds may be prone to include hip dysplasia, eye problems, and dental issues."</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_otherName">
        <item>Labrador, Lab</item>
        <item>Bouledogue Français</item>
        <item>Alsatian, Berger Allemand</item>
        <item>Flat-coated Retriever, Golden</item>
        <item>English Bulldog, British Bulldog</item>
        <item>English Beagle</item>
        <item>Pudel, Caniche</item>
        <item>Rott, Rottie</item>
        <item>Yorkshire, The Tomboy Boy</item>
        <item>Sausage Dog, Weiner Dog</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_origin">
        <item>United Kingdom</item>
        <item>England</item>
        <item>Germany</item>
        <item>Scotland</item>
        <item>England</item>
        <item>England</item>
        <item>Germany, France</item>
        <item>Germany</item>
        <item>England</item>
        <item>Germany</item>
    </string-array>
    <integer-array name="data_photo">
        <item>@drawable/labrador_retriever</item>
        <item>@drawable/french_bulldog</item>
        <item>@drawable/german_shepherd</item>
        <item>@drawable/golden_retriever</item>
        <item>@drawable/bulldog</item>
        <item>@drawable/beagle</item>
        <item>@drawable/poodle</item>
        <item>@drawable/rottweiler</item>
        <item>@drawable/yorkshire_terrier</item>
        <item>@drawable/dachsund</item>
    </integer-array>
</resources>